A Guide to the William H. Stein papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA127
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscripts, 1950-1975; 5; 3.52 Cubic Feet
  - Streptococcal Proteinase - Liu, 1964 (Box 1 of 2, Folder 2)
  - Sulfhydryl Manuscript (Box 2 of 2, Folder 3)
  - Takahashi Manuscript, 1 of 3 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Takahashi Manuscript, 2 of 3 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Takahashi Manuscript, 3 of 3 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Trypsin Inhibitors - Jones, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Structure and Enzymatic Activity of Proteins, 1 of 3 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Structure and Enzymatic Activity of Proteins, 2 of 3 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Structure and Enzymatic Activity of Proteins, 3 of 3 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - US National Committee, 1 of 3 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - US National Committee, 2 of 3 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - US National Committee, 3 of 3 (Box 45, Folder 6)
- Editorial Work, 1950-1975; 6; 3.52 Cubic Feet
  Includes correspondence and articles by other scientists.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by name of body editing was done for.
  - ACS, 1950 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - ACS Lilly Award, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - ASBC Council (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - ASBC Executive Secretary Communications, 1 of 2 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - ASBC Executive Secretary Communications, 2 of 2 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - ASBC Scientists Registry (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Annual Review of Biochemistry, 1 of 2 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Annual Review of Biochemistry, 2 of 2 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Archives of Biochemistry, 1 of 2 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Archives of Biochemistry, 2 of 2 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Biochemical Society of London, 1 of 3 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Biochemical Society of London, 2 of 3 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Biochemical Society of London, 3 of 3 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Board of Scientific Directors (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Current Journal of Biological Chemistry - Tabor, Editor, 1 of 3 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Current Journal of Biological Chemistry - Tabor, Editor, 2 of 3 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Current Journal of Biological Chemistry - Tabor, Editor, 3 of 3 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Council of Biology Editors (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Editorial Board and Committee Meetings, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Editorial Board and Committee Meetings, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Editorial Candidates (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Editorial Candidates Questionnaire (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Editorial Committee, 1955-1958 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Editorial Committee, 1955-1958 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Editorial Committee - Advertising (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Editorial Committee - Appointments and Retirements (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Editorial Committee - Correspondence (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Editorial Committee - Journal of Biological Chemistry (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Editorial Committee - Journal Policies (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Editorial Committee - Page Changes (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Editorial Committee - Preliminary Communications (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Edsall Volume (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Harte, Robert A., 1 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Harte, Robert A., 2 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - JBC (Journal of Biological Chemistry) Associate Editor (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - JBC Editor (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - JBC Reviews, 1 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - JBC Reviews, 2 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - JBC, 1972; 1 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - JBC, 1972; 2 of 2 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Journal of Lipid Research (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1 of 2 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 2 of 2 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - NIH Grants (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - NSF Grants, 1 of 4 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - NSF Grants, 2 of 4 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - NSF Grants, 3 of 4 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - NSF Grants, 4 of 4 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Nomenclature, 1 of 2 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Nomenclature, 2 of 2 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Referee Reports (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Science (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Scientific Advisory Committee (Box 53, Folder 7)
- Laboratory Notes, 1937-1970; 7; 3.08 Cubic Feet
  Includes notebooks and some lecture notes.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by subject. Most not dated.
  - Amino Acid Analysis, 1 of 2 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Amino Acid Analysis, 2 of 2 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Amino Acid Analyzer, 1 of 5 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Amino Acid Analyzer, 2 of 5 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Amino Acid Analyzer, 3 of 5 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Amino Acid Analyzer, 4 of 5 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Amino Acid Analyzer, 5 of 5 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Amino Acid Literature (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Amino Acids (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Argenine (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Autotitrator-Hirs (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Benzyloxy Salts (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Blood Coagulation (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Chromatography of Proteins (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Collagen (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Columbia Seminars (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Compound X, 1952 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Current Research Ideas (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - d-Peptiolaseo (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Determination of Amino Acids (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Determination of Proline (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Distribution of Coefficients and Amino Acids (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Elastin (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Extraction Apparatus (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Flavionic Acid (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Gelatin (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Gelatin and Collagen (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - General Amino Acid Salts (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Glyeine Analysis (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Ion Exchange (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Isolation from Starch Columns (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Isolation of Leucine (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Isolation of l-Serine (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Laboratory Plans (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Leucine Analysis (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Microanalysis (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Experiments (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Models (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Nasylates with l-Leucine (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - 1960 Ribonuclease Supply, 1 of 2 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - 1960 Ribonuclease Supply, 2 of 2 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Ninhydrin Bibliography (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Ninhydrin Data (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Nitronephthaleine (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Notebook from Harvard (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Notebook of Prints (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Old Prints (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Parks-Ribonuclease (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Partition Chromatography (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Partition Chromatography Calculations (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Pepsin (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Peptides (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Phenylalanine (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Proline and Hydroxy (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Protein Structure (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Precipitants in Amino Acid Analysis of Proteins (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Preparation of Various Sulfuric Acids (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Prints of Urine (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Proline (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Proline Content of Gelatin (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - p-Tyrosine Specific Rotation (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Reaction Time of NH2-N (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Reagents for Amino Acids (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Reports on Gelatin and Pepsin (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Resolution (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Silk (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Silk Isolation (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Silk Dioxpyridates (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Silk Partial Hydrolysis (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Silk Preparation (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Solubility of Various Amino Acid Salts (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Solubility Methods (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Solubility Products (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Specifications for Machines (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Starch Columns (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Streptococcal Proteinase (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Technicon Collector (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Tyroucline and Gramicidan (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Tryptophane (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Ultraviolet Spectra #1329 (Box 60, Folder 11)
- Subject Files, 1943-1970; 8; 1.32 Cubic Feet
  Includes laboratory and lecture notes, reprints and some correspondence on a variety of topics.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by subject.
  - ACS Reception, 1951 September 7 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Amino Acids and Histones (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Amino Acids and Mental Disease (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Analytical Chemistry (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Borohydride (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Calculations (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Crestfield-Analytical Chemistry, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Elastin Composition (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Histidine Residue (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Materials for Press (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Meteorites, 1 of 3 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Meteorites, 2 of 3 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Meteorites, 3 of 3 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Nachmansohn (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - NATO Course, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Nobel, 1 of 3 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Nobel, 2 of 3 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Nobel, 3 of 3 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Office of Scientific Research and Development (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Other ACS Journals (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Partition Chromatography (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Positions Open (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Science in Schools (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Sulfite and Proteins (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Travel Awards, 1 of 3 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Travel Awards, 2 of 3 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Travel Awards, 3 of 3 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Uremia (Box 63, Folder 7)
- Postdoctorals, 1947-1977; 9; 2.64 Cubic Feet
  Includes Masters and Doctoral dissertations of students Dr. Stein advised. Most are from Cornell University.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by last name of author.
  - Bartholeyns, 1 of 2 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Bartholeyns, 2 of 2 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Blackburn (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Burton, Louis E. (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Buston, Michael, 1 of 2 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Buston, Michael, 2 of 2 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Cole, R. David (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Drummond, Robert J. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Fletcher, Paul (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Gerwin, Brenda I. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Greene, Lewis J. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Guha, Arabinda (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Gundlach, Gerd (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Hayashi, Rikimaru (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Heinrikson, Robert L. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Hirs, Dr. Chiu, 1 of 2 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Hirs, Dr. Chiu, 2 of 2 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Hugli, T.E., 1 of 3 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Hugli, T.E., 2 of 3 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Hugli, T.E., 3 of 3 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Jailkhani, B.L. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Lee, Chong Kil (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Liao, 1 of 2 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Liao, 2 of 2 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Manning, James, 1 of 2 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Manning, James, 2 of 2 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Price, Paul, 1 of 2 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Price, Paul, 2 of 2 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Nigen, Alan (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Njikam, Njifutie (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Plapp, Bryce V. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Rajagopalan, T.G. (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Robinson, G.W. (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Saari (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Salnikow, Johann (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Scoffone, Ernesto (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Shaw, Denis (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Sogin (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Soper, Tom (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Spackmann, D.H. (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Stark, George R., 1 of 2 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Stark, George R., 2 of 2 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Takahashi, K. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Tallan, Harris H. (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Teh-Yung Liu, Darrel, 1 of 2 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Teh-Yung Liu, Darrel, 2 of 2 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Glynn (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Wang (Box 69, Folder 6)
- Slides, 10
  Arrangement
  No arrangement; slides not identified individually.
  Scope and Contents
  Includes slides used in conjunction with lectures.
  - Slides for Lectures (Box 70, Box 72, Box 71, Box 74, Box 73, Box 75, Box 76, Box 77, Box 78)
- Audio Tapes, 1960-1980; 11; 0.25 Cubic Feet
  5 recordings including Memorial of Stein given by Prof. Moore and 4 lectures by Stein himself at various occasions.
  Arranged in chronological order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
  - SYMPOSIUM ON MICROSTRUCTURE OF PROTEINS, ACS MEETING, September 1960 (Box 78, 1/4 inch audio tape AV 6960)
    RAC is unable to provide access to the original item, due to the specialized equipment necessary to facilitate playback. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
    Chair William H. Stein.
  - CRYSTALS AND IONS, 29 December 1961; Stein, William H. (Box 78, 1/4 inch audio tape AV 6959)
  - DR. PHILLIPS LECTURES, 1962 (Box 78, 1/4 inch audio tape AV 6962)
    Recorded at Haverford College.
  - SCIENCE CONVOCATION, 20 March 1973 (Box 78, 1/4 inch audio tape AV 6961)
    Recorded at Low Library.
  - RECOLLECTIONS OF WILLIAM H. STEIN, 6 February 1980; Moore, Stanford (Box 78, 1/4 inch audio tape AV 6963)
    Recorded at Caspary Auditorium. Memorial given by Stanford Moore.
    Stein, William H.